

# Aaron Jude D Cruz

Data Science / Data Analysis / Research

Data Analyst, experienced in interpreting and analyzing data to drive successful business solution. With interest in analyzing raw data, brings excellent communication abilities and hands on experience in creating a dashboards with a story to tell.

aaronjude96@gmail.com

Bengaluru, India

in linkedin.com/in/aaron-dcruz-b28771145

+918891949520

www.hackerrank.com/aaronjude96

github.com/aj081

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Associate Consultant | Analytics Ernst & Young

03/2022 - 08/2022

Bengaluru, India

https://www.ey.com/en\_us

CoE - Client and Audit support

- Primarily worked on audit analytics using EY data analytics tools, ETL tool and Python scripting.
- o Designed and implemented ETL workflows using Alteryx.
- Conducted data mining, data modelling and created dashboards in coordination with the finance department.
- Conducted analysis on various aspects saving revenue up to 1M.

# Machine Learning - Data Associate Amazon

12/2018 - 01/2021 Chennai, India

A.I Enhancement in Alexa

- Data cleaning, Preparation and Preliminary analysis using Amazon Redshift, Advanced Excel and Amazon analytics tool.
- Compiled data and distinguished trends by creating dashboard to support the team in critical product related decision-making.
- Identified patterns of failure and developed root cause reports to address the problem, successfully revealing insights that boosted efficiency by 7%.

### **PROJECTS**

Restaurant Ratings Analysis and Prediction. (11/2021 - 02/2022)

- Primary Goal: To perform extensive Exploratory Data Analysis on the Zomato Dataset and build an appropriate Machine Learning Model.
- Solution: The Data was scrapped from Zomato and Analyzed using python. The dataset consisted of 51,000 rows and 17 features, and the best suited Machine Learning model was built to predict the restaurant ratings based on the certain features.
- Result: Best performance was obtained by Decision Tree Model with a performance score of 99%

#### **EDUCATION**

# Post Graduate Diploma in Data Science Manipal Academy of Higher Education

01/2021 - 02/2022

CGPA- 9.5

Courses

- Programming for Data Science using Python.
- Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence.
- Data Analysis and Visualization using Python.
- Data Science on AWS Cloud Platform.

## **SKILLS**



# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Recognized for Insisting in high standards (E&Y)
- Won best performer award in Team Alexa (Amazon)

### **CERTIFICATES**

Successfully completed Python programming bootcamp (03/2021 - 07/2021)

Udemy

Certified Python programmer (04/2021 - 05/2021)

Hacker Rank and Coursera

Certified SQL programmer (04/2021 - 05/2021)

Hacker Rank and Coursera

#### **SOFT SKILLS**

